# Ali Taei Semiromi - Senior Front-end Engineer



# **CONTACTS**

Ali.taei.semiromi@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio | Medium | Mobile number: 647070230

# **SUMMARY**

I'm a Senior Front-end Engineer with more than 9 years of experience. I have a self-taught spirit and a passion for Front-end Development, which I see as a perfect blend of art and technology. While I've primarily worked with JavaScript and React throughout my career, I'm always open to learning new technologies. I've successfully mentored developers, helping them grow professionally. I've initiated projects to drive innovation, maintain a keen eye for detail, and consistently stay updated with new technologies and best practices in the field. I enjoy Music, Books, Photography, Board games, Running, and Travel.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.Js, NodeJs, Code review, Team work, Critical thinking, SOLID, Redux, Redux-Toolkit, React-Query, Git, E2E Testing, Unit Testing, Jest, Testing Library, Cypress, Playwright, Storybook, Responsive Design, Jira, Scrum, Agile Development, SPA, Socket.IO, REST API, Parcel.Js, Webpack, Rollup, Vite, Yarn, NPM.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

CLIQ Digital, Amsterdam, Netherlands — Senior Front-end Engineer

Mar 2023 - present (1 yr 8 mos)

At CLIQ Digital we sell subscription-based streaming services that bundle movies & series, music, audiobooks, sports and games to consumers globally.

- Lead the front-end team, onboard new developers, conduct code reviews, and engage in pair programming sessions.
- Successfully launched CMS and licence management tool for the company, which is responsible for managing 500,000 items. Architecture design of Content Management System using Domain-driven design (DDD), Next.js, React-Query, MUI, TypeScript, and Storybook, following clean code principles, best practices, unit testing, and documentation.
- Introducing a component library to the company and developing common components as packages to enhance reusability across projects.
- Mentor and coach junior developers to learn fundamentals and best practices in front-end development.

<u>Passionate People</u>, Amsterdam, Netherlands — Senior Front-end Engineer

Sep 2022 - Mar 2023 (7 mos)

Passionate People is a JavaScript consultancy in the Netherlands. The Company is behind <u>JsWorld</u> conference.

- Assisted backstage at the VueJs and JsWorld conference in 2023.
- Maintained the primary website and introduced new features.
- Developed internal dashboards using technologies such as React, Next.js, TypeScript, and Storybook.

<u>Snappfood</u>, Tehran, Iran — *Senior Front-end Engineer* 

July 2021 - Aug 2022 (1 yr 2 mos)

Snappfood with 2.5 million users per day is the largest online food ordering and grocery shopping platform in Iran.

 Working with 30 front-end engineers at Iran's largest online food ordering and grocery platform provided invaluable learning opportunities from colleagues with diverse experiences. Through frequent pair programming sessions, cross-team feature deliveries, and weekly knowledge-sharing meetings, I significantly enhanced my skills and broadened my expertise.

- Worked in a team of 10 people closely with designers, developers, QA engineers, scrum masters, and product managers using Scrum.
- Developed features and maintained mobile and desktop applications using React, TypeScript, Next.js, SCSS, Redux, Storybook, Jest, Testing Library.
- Onboarded new developers and created a document for onboarding.
- Introduced unit and end-to-end (E2E) testing through five technical presentations, leading to fewer bugs and improved
  quality in the application.

# Pishgam Vista, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Developer

December 2019 - June 2021 (1 yr 2 mos)

- Created front-end projects using JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Redux-thunk, Socket.IO, and REST API.
- Reduced development time by creating common components.
- Collaborated with 8 other group members of designers, developers, and product owners.
- Debugged 3 large legacy codes and refactored them for better performance and clean code.

#### Nabzino, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Developer

March 2019 - September 2019 (7 mos)

- Implemented dashboards for our internal projects using React.
- Converted UI landing design into a responsive web page.
- Launched a game campaign with a team of developers and designers within a tight deadline, using Vue.js.
- Released video gallery using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, and JavaScript, it increased average session duration by 5%.

# Arta Seo, Esfahan, Iran — Front-end Developer / WordPress Developer

March 2018 - February 2019 (1 yr)

- Communicated with customers to create responsive websites based on their needs.
- Converted UI designs into WordPress responsive websites.
- Introduced WordPress plugin development to the company.
- Mentored a team of 10 interns to learn HTML, CSS, and WordPress.
- Reduced data entry time to 30% by optimizing the website panel.

## Asr-e Digital, Esfahan, Iran — WordPress Developer / Website Manager

February 2014 - January 2017 (3 yrs)

- Proposed creating a blog to publish product reviews and news in Technology, this led to improving Alexa rank 2 times.
- Directed 3 translators to translate English content to Persian and content editing according to SEO.
- Customized a blog using WordPress for a better user experience.

## **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering — Associate's degree

# **LANGUAGES**

English (Advanced level) Persian (Native)